<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on J. D. Mitchell</title>
    <link>https://james-d-mitchell.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on J. D. Mitchell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© J. D. Mitchell</copyright><atom:link href="https://james-d-mitchell.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An implementation of the Todd-Coxeter algorithm in python3</title>
      <link>https://james-d-mitchell.github.io/posts/2021-07-11-todd-coxeter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://james-d-mitchell.github.io/posts/2021-07-11-todd-coxeter/</guid>
      <description>This page is a companion to the paper The Todd-Coxeter Algorithm for Semigroups and Monoids by T. D. H. Coleman, J. D. Mitchell, F. L. Smith, and M. Tsalakou. On this page we give an implementation of the two strategies for congruence enumeration described in the paper in python3. The code on this page is expository, and should probably not be used for anything serious. There are many optimization that could be applied, but we opted not to do these in order to keep the code short.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://james-d-mitchell.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://james-d-mitchell.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>This is the webpage of James D. Mitchell. I am a professor of mathematics at the School of Mathematics and Statistics at the University of St Andrews. I&amp;rsquo;m currently interested in computational semigroup theory, and topological algebra.
The website accompanying the paper ‘Groups that together with any transformation generate regular semigroups or idempotent generated semigroups’ by J. Araújo, J. D. Mitchell and Csaba Schneider is available here.
Address Mathematical Institute,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data</title>
      <link>https://james-d-mitchell.github.io/data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://james-d-mitchell.github.io/data/</guid>
      <description>This page is under construction&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://james-d-mitchell.github.io/publ/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://james-d-mitchell.github.io/publ/</guid>
      <description>A list of publications by J. D. Mitchell on MathSciNet.
 (with R. Cirpons) &amp;lsquo;Polynomial time multiplication and normal forms in free bands&amp;rsquo;, submitted; https://arxiv.org/abs/2209.05334 (with T. D. H. Coleman, F. L. Smith, and M. Tsalakou) &amp;lsquo;The Todd-Coxeter Algorithm for Semigroups and Monoids&amp;rsquo;, preprint; https://arxiv.org/abs/2203.11148 (with M. Anagnostopoulou-Merkouri and Z. Mesyan) &amp;lsquo;Properties of Congruence Lattices of Graph Inverse Semigroups&amp;rsquo;, submitted; https://arxiv.org/abs/2108.08277 (with J. East and J. Jonušas) &amp;lsquo;Generating the monoid of 2×2 matrices over max-plus and min-plus semirings&amp;rsquo;, preprint; https://arxiv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://james-d-mitchell.github.io/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://james-d-mitchell.github.io/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The number of monogenic subsemigroups of the full transformation monoid</title>
      <link>https://james-d-mitchell.github.io/posts/2016-09-02-monogenic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://james-d-mitchell.github.io/posts/2016-09-02-monogenic/</guid>
      <description>Mathematics In this post we show how to count the number of monogenic subsemigroups of the full transformation monoid up to isomorphism.
Throughout this post, we denote the natural numbers \(\{0, 1, \ldots\}\) by \({\mathbb{N}}\). The symmetric group and full transformation semigroup on \(\{1, \ldots, n\}\), \(n\in {\mathbb{N}}\), are denoted \(S_n\) and \(T_n\), respectively. A subsemigroup of a semigroup \(S\) is monogenic if it can be generated by a single element; monogenic subsemigroups of finite groups are just cyclic subgroups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://james-d-mitchell.github.io/soft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://james-d-mitchell.github.io/soft/</guid>
      <description>GAP  Digraphs deposited GAP package, 2022. Semigroups deposited GAP package, 2022. SgpDec - Hierarchical composition and decomposition of finite permutation groups and transformation semigroups (by A. Egri-Nagy and C. Nehaniv with some contributions by me) deposited GAP package, 2022. Smallsemi - a library of small semigroups (with A. Distler) deposited GAP package, 2022.  C++  libsemigroups C++ library for semigroups and monoids, 2022.  python  libsemigroups_pybind11 python package for using libsemigroups via pybind11, (with M.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
